All right. Good evening. Um,
good evening everyone. Uh,
y'all go ahead and put a
one in the chat. [clears throat]
Uh, I just want to make sure that you
guys are able to hear me.
So, um I am jumping on tonight, guys, uh
to do
uh one of
uh well the first of what will be um
multiple
uh presentations on
my new photoology
bible suite.
So, uh, yeah. Um, I want to just again
make sure that you guys could hear me.
So, uh, just go ahead and put that one
in the chat. All right. Excellent.
Excellent. Excellent.
Um,
yeah. So again guys,
thanks to everyone
um to uh really just take some time
to By the way, thank you for everyone
that has been praying for me over the
last uh over the last week. Uh all
prayers are appreciated.
Um thank you for lifting me up. Thank
you for lifting my family up. Um all
right, guys. So
tonight, um,
we're going to be talking about the
photo theology
Bible study software. And, um,
[clears throat]
you can see it on the screen behind me.
Uh, but I'm going to actually be sharing
my screen. So, uh, we're going to walk
through this app. Now, we're not going
to do it all tonight because there is
too much in this app. All right. Um,
some of you may already be familiar with
the app. Uh, may or I should say the
software. Um,
but I'm going to share my screen. I'm
going to kind of walk through some
things. And again, this is going to be
ongoing for uh for some time because
there is a lot in this uh Bible
software.
So, um, with that said, guys, let's go
ahead and jump in and I'm going to share
my screen here. Uh, so for those of you
who may be hearing about this for the
first time, uh, this is the photo
theology Bible study suite.
And, um, I will just give you a little
bit of background
about this. So for
uh over 20 years I've been teaching the
um
uh an approach to Bible study called
photo theology. And um what this
approach does is it basically
helps you to understand the Bible
um by using images. So, if you've heard
the the the the phrase, a picture is
worth a thousand words, that is the
concept that I apply to Bible study. So,
that when I'm studying the Bible, I'm
always
uh um having seeing mental pictures of
the text I'm studying, of the story I'm
studying. There's a storyline being
created. It's almost as if every time I
preach a sermon, I feel like I feel as
if I'm creating a movie, like I'm
producing a movie. Um, I'm taking the
various scenes of the Bible and putting
them in in a particular order that is
going to bring that aha moment, if you
will. So, uh, this is the system of
photo theology. Uh it is a system that
is uh that is heavily dependent upon
learning how to think in pictures. And
so I've been teaching uh um uh classes
on this for years and years and years
now. Army Bible Camp, if any of you have
ever been to an Army Bible Camp, you're
you're familiar with photo theology. If
you've heard me preach, you're familiar
with photo theology. Um I have a
photoology class that I have been
teaching for the last five to six years
now. It is the same class and we have
been going through the principles of
photoology
um for that long. And um so this is a
very extensive
system of Bible study. Okay.
And um
the the whole basis of this uh of this
approach to Bible study, we we we use
what we call the photo theology palace.
The photoology palace, imagine a a
palace with eight floors and across
these eight floors are 37 rooms. Each
room represents a principle
and and uh within each room are multiple
aspects of that particular principle. So
[clears throat]
the idea behind this is that I could
take one verse and actually carry that
verse to each room in the photo theology
palace and study it from a different
perspective, a different angle, a
different principle. one text I can move
it through all 37 rooms through all
eight floors and get a different
perspective a different understanding
from that one text and so this is the
system that I've been teaching and now I
have made it um available in a software
program now at first the goal was to
make it an app and it still is going to
be an app but you guys I have to tell
you that I use this on my computer way
more than I do on my phone, right? Uh
for those of you who have who have uh
who are familiar with uh my Bible
teachings, you know that I've often uh
encourage people to use Esord. And
there's several other Bible softwares
>> [clears throat]
>> um that that people use that I utilize.
And so in creating this software, I
wanted to basically take an esord, a
logos,
um a blue letter Bible, and then amplify
it by adding the photo theology
principles. And um that's what this
software is. It is you guys. I don't
even I'm not even sure how to express to
you uh how powerful
this photo theology Bible study suite
is.
Um, if you if you try to go to like uh
chat GPT or any other AI program and try
to ask it, you know, this question about
the Bible or that, it's going to give
you answers. But this Bible software is
actually trained to use the photoology
principles, which makes it different
from anything else out there. Okay. So,
um
this uh this software by the way
um I'm going to put the address for this
software in the screen uh in the chat so
that you guys can have can see how to
get access to it. Um
so it is photoologybible.com.
Some of you may may already be familiar
with um uh the photo
theology
app.com.
Um same site but is the preferred uh
address um for you to get to this
software. Okay. All right. So guys, um
with all of that said, um this Bible
study suite, this Bible study um uh
program
basically is everything that I have been
teaching over the last 20 plus years uh
brought down into one software. That's
what this is. Okay. So I want to kind of
walk you through an overview of this
app. And as you can see on the screen um
[clears throat]
uh let me
okay so you can see here um you got two
options right before you come to this
app you can remain at the surface where
you may continue as you are you will
still read the Bible you will still find
comfort you will still hear familiar
truths you will stay where most remain
moving verse to verse devotion to
devotion
never quite seeing how it all fits
together. Nothing will change. Or
you can enter the palace. You may step
inside. Beyond this point, the Bible
will no longer appear flat. Patterns
will emerge. Connections will form. What
one see what once seemed distant will
begin to speak across time. This is not
passive study. This is not
entertainment. This is not for the
hurried or the casual. And uh I hope
that you enter in. I hope that you enter
in. So that's what we're going to do,
guys. We're going to go ahead and um
uh enter into the app. Um and again, I'm
going to show you a a short overview.
Now, we're not going to we're not going
to be super long tonight because again,
there's way too much to cover um of all
that this software can do. And again,
for those of you that are using this on
your phone, you can use it on your
phone, but I definitely encourage you to
um to use this on your computer for for
a deeper and thorough a more thorough
experience with the software. Okay. So,
[clears throat]
let me walk you through the tabs. And I
just want you to take a look at how many
different tabs there are in this
program. Okay,
these are all the different tabs. So,
you can see why I'm saying uh it'll take
it'll take a minute, a good minute, a
good long minute, right? It'll take some
time, some some some serious time to
actually go through each one of these
tabs. But,
um let me start with the palace tab. And
uh we'll go through this in in in
greater detail um in in future videos,
but the palace tab which is kind which
is the first page is basically where the
palace lives. All right. So you can see
as you scrolling down you can see this
is floor one of the palace and these are
the rooms of the palace. There's the
story room, the imagination room, the 24
frames per second room, the Bible
rendered room, the translation room, the
gems room. Each of these rooms represent
a different principle. Um, so I'll give
you an example. Uh, let me click on the
story room. And the story room, these
the first floor is very basic. Okay?
It's basically uh um um a a beginning
approach to the Bible. The story room,
for example, is really all about making
sure that your palace, your imaginary
palace has enough stories stored in it
because the stories are going to be the
building blocks of your study, right?
So, the more stories you're familiar
with in the Bible, the better you're
going to be able to make connections
between things you may have never
thought had a connection before.
So, in the story room on this app, it
just teaches you, you know, hey, how do
how do you learn how to not memorize
stories, but lock them, you know, into
your palace, right, into your mind. Um,
so there are different techniques. You
can you can story map a a story. You can
uh look at the character portrait of the
story. You can look at the sequence
David the story of David and Goliath.
What is the sequence? Right? And I know
this sounds very simple but again there
are a lot of people who are very basic
in their understanding of the Bible and
you have to start at the beginning. So
this app this software this software
starts you know
it it covers everything from the most
basic level of understanding to the most
scholarly level of understanding no
matter where you are in your Bible study
journey. Um this Bible study software is
designed to cover you where you are and
bring you further than where you are.
Okay. So
um
if I continue to scroll down and you'll
see here this whole room is just you
know h how to how to memorize stories
not memorize but how to lock the stories
in your mind how to uh [clears throat]
um
the methodologies examples right just
learning how to lock these stories and
then you'll go scroll down you'll see a
Bible story library then the Bible the
story library. Basically, what these
what this is is it's just all right,
we're just going to kind of summarize
all the stories of the Bible, right? And
this Bible study, this Bible story
library will continue to grow. So, for
example, if I'm in the book of Genesis
and I'm just scrolling through and
looking at the different stories, now
there are more stories in Genesis than
just what you see here. So that's why
I'm saying it continues to be populated,
but basic stories, right? It's just
giving you a summary of the stories of
each book of the Bible. Okay, so that's
pretty neat if you are just learning
about the Bible. If you're just uh uh
getting familiar with the stories of the
Bible, uh this is all in the story room.
Okay, this is all in the story room. And
um
let me just go back to books real quick.
And again you'll see Exodus, 2 Samuel, 2
Chronicles, Job. Again, the there are
the the the uh story library is still
being populated. So the next time you
click on, you're going to see more
stories across each book of the Bible.
But again, it's a basic beginning,
right? To help you understand here's how
I lock in the stories of the story room.
All right. So, let me go back to the
palace and um and again, so here are all
the different rooms. I'm going just
click on one more just to show you an
example. The symbols and types room. In
the symbols and types room, this is all
about learning the symbols and types of
the Bible, right? Uh and again you'll
see explanations, you'll see exercises.
Map your first symbol. Uh what does the
lamb represent in scripture? Um you can
again as you continue to scroll down you
will see a symbols library and you'll
see like colors, numbers, beasts and
animals, objects, nature, right? symbols
of nature, names, uh body parts,
materials, actions and rituals, places.
All of these are are li this is a
library containing the various symbols.
And again, what I want you to understand
is that these libraries will continue to
grow. They're just kind of giving
examples of here's how you really unpack
this room, this principle. There's tons
of symbols across the scripture, right?
Tons of stories across the scripture. So
again, um,
if I click in any one of these rooms in
the palace, you're going to see the same
thing. So, uh, that's floor number two.
Here's floor number three, the freestyle
floor. Now, for those of you who may
remember our freestyle Wednesdays, which
are coming back.
Um, this is kind of where that that
principle for freestyling came from,
right? So, you have the nature of
freestyle. How do I take object lessons
from nature and freestyle those? In
other words, how do I take the grass or
the thunder or the rain or the the wind
or um something from the animal kingdom
like the ants or the bees? How do I take
these these things and apply
biblical principles or look at them in
their natural setting and pull object
lessons of biblical principles?
uh um from [snorts] these things that
I'm beholding in nature. Right? So
that's the nature freestyle room.
There's the personal freestyle room.
Looking into your own life and saying,
"What things have I gone through in my
life that I can pull biblical object
lessons uh that I can pull object
lessons from the uh object lessons or
principles, biblical principles from my
own experience and apply them to the
word of God." Right? So again,
um, we have, uh, the Bible freestyle,
which I'm going to get into a little bit
later in another program. We don't have
time to do that now. The historical
social freestyle, and then there's the
listening room. If I go to floor four,
um, [clears throat] you will see here is
where the meat of photoology begins
uh to really unfold. Right? These are
the rooms where if you if you've heard
me preach,
um these are the principles you're
listening to in action, right? So,
there's the concentration room. How do I
find Christ in the story? That's the
concentration room. We're learning how
to focus and lock in on Christ. Where is
Christ in this prophecy? Where is Christ
in this text? Where is Christ in this
parable? Where is Christ in this
historical account? Where is Christ in
this symbol? Right? That is the
concentration room. Um, and I click on
the concentration room and you'll see
the explanation. The concentration room
trains you to see Christ through the
lens of his three-fold office, prophet,
priest, and king, etc. Those are whole
explanation there, right? As I scroll
down in the concentration room, there
are exercises, games, right? Different
things that are going to help you to
learn how to lock in on Christ when you
are studying any portion of the Bible.
Now, I have to introduce you to Jeves,
okay? Because you're you're you've
probably seen Jeeves uh in this in uh on
a couple of the pages that I've already
shown you. And Jeeves is basically the
photo theology AI that is in this
software to help you with any question
that you have. So, if you're in the
concentration room, for example, and
you're like, man, how do I find Christ
in uh in the story of I'm going to use
something simple, David and Goliath? And
let's say you're really struggling like
where is Jesus in in the story of David
and Goliath? You can go over and ask
Jesus
in this story. Help me find Jesus in
this verse. Help me find Jesus in this
parable. And so Jeeves is there almost
as your photoology assistant, right? Uh
this software is not designed
to study for you. That's not the purpose
of this of this this software. It's
designed to teach you how to think photo
theologically,
right? It's designed to teach you how to
think using images and pictures and how
to make connections so that you can do
this yourself. Okay. Um All right. So,
uh let me go back and again so you see
all the floors. Here's floor five. Uh
here is floor six. Here is floor seven.
These are all the different and we we
will go over all of these guys. We're
going to walk through these um uh in in
future um uh videos, but what I want you
to see is a basic picture of how this
software works. Floor eight is the
mastery floor. And uh basically what
this is is it's it's when
all these other rooms
as you have mastered these other rooms
becomes reflexive where you're no longer
thinking in terms of let me look at this
text in the context of the five
dimensions room or let me look at this
text in the context of the mathematics
room. What is the mathematics room? The
mathematics room is where we look at the
prophetic the prophetic math of God. So,
we're talking about the 120-year
prophecy of Noah. We're talking about
the 400year prophecy of each of uh the
children of Israel in cap in Egyptian
bondage. We're talking about the 70-year
prophecy. We're talking about the 70we
prophecy. We're talking about the
1260ear prophecy. We're talking about
the 2300 day prophecy. How do these uh
six time prophecies correlate with any
given passage I'm studying? Right? How
How does [clears throat]
uh Matthew 24 correlate with the 70we
prophecy or the 70-year prophecy for
that matter?
If I can explain it this way, right?
When you're learning to ride a Bible for
the first time, um you're focused on
training wheels, right? as a c as a ch
as a kid you're riding the bike you know
you're thinking about that the training
wheels are holding you up but there
comes a time where you no longer need
the training wheels the principle
remains you've learned how to balance
the bike but you no longer need the
training wheel in that same way um when
I teach my students the photo theology
principles we start off you know really
locked in on the different rooms What is
the eight cy what what are the eight
cycles? What is the juice room? What is
the mathematics room? How do I apply the
verse uh in the mathematics room? How do
I apply the verse in the connect six
room? But the goal is actually to get
the student to no longer even think of
those rooms. When I'm putting together
my Bible studies
or I'm studying the Bible or putting
together a sermon, I'm not thinking, let
me take this verse into the mathematics
room. Let me take this room into the
into the five dimensions and look at
which dimension m really jumps out to
me. No, I am naturally thinking through
these processes without even thinking
about it. And that is kind of the basis
the idea behind this eighth floor. So if
we would say it this way, this eighth
floor is like uh mastery level, right?
um where you're no longer thinking
through the rooms uh intentionally as
you're reading the Bible. Stuff is just
jumping out to you. Connections are just
being made and the the spirit is guiding
in a way where it's almost as if you're
in the flow, right? You're in this flow
where you're reading the text and you're
like, "Man, there's Jesus right there."
You're reading the story and you're
like, man, this connects with the seven
churches in Revelation chapter chapter 1
and two and three. This connects with,
you know, the prophecy of of Daniel 7,
the the lion leopard bear uh the lion
bear leopard uh dragon. You're beginning
to it becomes reflexive. That's the
whole idea. Okay. So guys, um the one of
the neat things about this palace uh
concept is that the software will teach
you each room
so that
you learn to master the room. Okay, you
learn to master the room.
Um okay, so guys, I'm going to go ahead
and move on. I'm I'm going to show you a
few more things and then we're going to
wrap it up for tonight. But remember,
we're going to be going into a whole lot
more detail. And for for some of you who
have been try who were trying this a
little bit earlier and you found some
glitches, we've been working through the
glitches. Um, and it is it is a lot
uh more sturdy now as I have been
building it out. Um, so again, uh, it's
it it continues to to,
uh, just get deeper, stronger, more
solid. Um,
so, uh, let me show you guys the photo
theology study Bible. So, I've skipped
my church space because this space here,
um, and I'll talk about this another
time, is is literally for churches that
want their own space on the app so that
their members can use the app to study,
to create studies, to lead out in Bible
studies, to learn how to study the word
of God. So, that's another section that
we're going to talk about um uh at
another time, but I want to take you to
the photo theology study bible, which is
like one of my very favorite parts of
this software. So, in this, and again,
this is just a brief overview, okay? So,
we're not going into great detail, but I
just want to show you. Let me let me
just go to a a simple chapter here. So,
we'll go to
We'll go to John
uh chapter We'll go to John chapter. And
by the way guys, so I know that earlier,
so some of you signed up for the
photoology GPT,
which I had presented before this
software program was done, and you've
been on that photo theology GPT. If if
you have subscribed for the photo
theology GPT,
you will automatically get free access
to this app. You don't have to to
subscribe to this app. If you're on the
photo theology GPT already and you
subscribe to one of them, email me, let
me know. You will have access to this
app without having to subscribe. Okay?
And what I'm going to show you is that
if you go over in the tab section to
GPTs,
you will see all those GPTs, right? We
had the photo theology GPT, the uh kid
GPT, the Daniel and Revelation GPT, and
the apologetics GPT. So, it's all there.
Um,
all right. So, you'll see this this will
look familiar to to you, right? for
those of you that were on those GPTs.
So, in other words, guys, this software
has all those GPTs that I created
before. Um,
okay. So, I just wanted to point that
out again for those of you that may that
may be using the the GPTs that I had um
released probably about maybe five four
or five months ago. Um, I'm going to
strongly encourage you to get on this.
It is 10 times ten times ten times
better than what I was presenting to you
before. Okay. So in the photo theology
study Bible
um
so you'll see here this is John chapter
3 and uh I'm going to show you that
again it's too much to show you in one
setting. Um but let me let me just show
you this for example. So I can click on
any word um and the
um
the Greek or the Hebrew of that word is
going to come up. Right? If you're in
the New Testament, Greek. If you're in
the Old Testament, the Hebrew. Click on
any word and you'll see it populate uh
with the meaning of that word in its
original language. All right. So, uh,
let me I'mma close that out and just,
um, show you a couple things here. So,
in this in this um
in this Bible, the photo theology study
Bible, if I hit principle mode, okay,
I'm just going to show you this and I'm
just leave it here. What it's going to
do is it's going to pull
any random
it's going to pull randomly principles
from the photo theology palace and apply
those principles to the text. Okay. So
for example uh that which is born of the
flesh is flesh. That which is born of
the spirit is spirit. And what you're
going to see are four different
principles, right? Four different
principles that are from the photo
theology palace that will actually
address tie that principle into the
text. Right? So let me uh let me go
here. Let me go here. Actually,
I'm going to click on unleaven bread,
which is part of the um the the uh feast
room principle, right? And in the feast
room principle, it's going to have all
the feasts, unleaven bread, first
fruits, uh Passover, etc. And what this
is going to do is it's going to show us
how the the the teaching of unleavened
bread, right, putting away of sin,
applies to this verse. Now, here's the
thing I like about this, guys. You would
probably never stop to think, hey, how
would unleaven bread, the feast of
unleavened bread, connect with this
verse? That which is born of the flesh
is flesh, and that which is born of the
spirit is spirit. So what this software
is doing is it's teaching you to think
outside the box, right? While remaining
inside the box, it's teaching you how to
[clears throat]
how to think through connections that
you may have never thought thought of on
your own because you just weren't
thinking I could think like that. But
when you start training your mind to
think like that, now you're like, hm, I
wonder what the feast of first fruits,
how the feast of first fruits may
connect with this. You'll see this
refresh button right here. If I hit that
refresh button, it's going to pull four
totally new principles from the palace
to apply
to the verse.
Okay. So,
um, and this is for every verse, guys.
Every verse. I just hit refresh and it's
going to pull up new principles. New
principles all from the photo theology
palace and apply it to that particular
text.
All right. So, that's I'm not going to
go yet into the link mode. I'm not going
to go yet into the commentaries mode.
I'm not even going to go yet into into
one of my most favorite aspects of this,
which is the audio, Bible, and
commentary.
Maybe I'll go into this a little bit.
The audio Bible and commentary. You can
actually listen to the Bible, but then
there is a photo theology commentary
where you can listen to the to the verse
and then listen to the commentary
read to you on that verse utilizing
photo theology principles to apply to
that verse. So it is a dynamic
commentary. By the way, this also has
all your typical commentaries like
Matthew Henry, Adam Clark, um, Albert
Barnes, etc. So, if you want to look at
a at a at a traditional commentary, you
can look at it. But if you want to see
the photo theology principles applied to
the verse, you can actually go through.
I'm going to show you this very quickly.
[clears throat and cough]
So,
I'm in the Bible mode. If I click on
commentary,
uh let's see commentary
and then I click on click on a
particular verse. So I'm going to say
this verse right here. Uh and now you'll
see here the Jes commentary. So this is
the photo theology commentary. It's
going to comment on that verse. Now
here's the powerful thing about this
guys. And y'all think I'm playing when I
say this is powerful because first of
all, if if I click revealed
revealed commentary, it's going to tell
me naturally what principles are already
in the text.
If I click apply commentary, I can now
go through and say to Jesus, hey, when
you're commenting on this verse, I want
you to include anything that may be
symbolic. I want you to include a nature
freestyle. I want you to include, make
sure you show me Jesus in the text. Um,
I want you to include a principle from
the connect six room uh from the
patterns room and then
see see all the options. See all the
options and then you generate the
commentary and it'll give you a
generated commentary on that text
utilizing those principles. you guys.
Oh, and for those of you who just asked,
Clint,
see that right there?
Yes.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Spirit of prophecy is
included in the commentary.
All right. So guys, that that is
that is the uh photo theology study
bible. And that's not everything on the
study Bible tab, but I'm just showing
you bits and pieces. Okay. Um, let me
scroll over very quickly to the
devotionals. I'm going to show you two
more tabs. Uh, the devotionals and I
will also show you um, one more tab and
I'll show you what that is in a second.
So, let me click on the devotionals. And
guys, in the devotional tab, this is
this is really this is really neat,
y'all. So in the devotional tab, I can
create
ask uh the software to create a devotion
for me for the day. A quick devotion. I
can create a devotional plan. Hey, I
would like a devotion
um taking me for the next six weeks
through the sanctuary or through the
last week of Christ's life or through
the Exodus. These are just already kind
of like subjects you can choose or you
can create your own subject,
you guys. I'm just saying. I'm just
saying y'all. I'm just saying. Okay. So,
I can also create a profile. So, let's
say that there's someone I know that,
you know, [clears throat] may be going
through a difficult time, may be going
through a difficult part in their
Christian journey. um maybe struggling
with something or just, you know, I know
what this person's going through and I
want to create a s a devotional
um series just for this person. If I
click create profile,
I can choose to create a profile for an
individual. I could do it for a
classroom. If you're a teacher, I could
do it for a family. You could have a
devote you could create a a dating
devotion. You can create a spousal
devotion. Um, you can put the person's
name. You can say, "Here's the
relationship. Here's my relationship to
the person. Here's the age group of the
person."
And after you choose all of this, it's
then going to ask you, okay, uh, so let
me just go, let's say individual.
I'm just going to say Henry.
Uh, I'll pick,
um, an avatar. I'm going to say Henry is
a friend. Uh he is between the age of 31
and 60. And then
what it's then going to do, it's going
to give me categories. What's Henry
going through? Um is he dealing with any
of these issues right here? You see all
these issues? Is he is he dealing with
any of these struggles? And then you So
Henry
uh Henry is my friend
that just lost his job
and is really
discouraged. And you go and then you go
ahead and click create commentary. And
it's going to ask you do you want to I
mean commentary create devotional. And
it's going to ask you uh is this
devotional for 7 days, 14 days, 21 days,
40 days, how long do you want it? And
then it'll create a devotion. And every
day it will produce a devotional that
you can then text or email to that
friend, to that
child, to that parent,
whoever it might be.
So,
this devotional aspect of the app, guys,
is very powerful because it is a really
neat way to be able to minister to
people on a daily basis, just sending
them devotions of encouragement. Um, all
right. So, let me show you one more one
more, guys. One more tab. I'm going to
show you this uh analyze my thoughts
tab. So, I just clicked on analyze my
thoughts.
And
this is another one of my very favorite
um very favorite tabs, you guys.
So, in this on this page,
let's say that I have a thought, right?
I'm like, h
um
now it's not a question. You can ask a
question. But this is for thought.
So for example,
um I just preached a sermon this past
week on um the priesthood of Melzdc
and how when Jesus says um except you be
born again, you cannot enter the kingdom
of God.
And my thought was so let me let me
share with you my thought. So
I wonder if
uh Jesus
saying that one must be born again
can connect with the labor
and also
uh connect with the idea that only
priests
could
um wash
at the labor
and thus only
priests could enter into the presence of
God
of God. So when uh Jesus is inviting us
um to be born again, he is inviting us
to be priests.
Okay. Um
Elena, yes. Uh so I just mentioned that
a little bit earlier. Maybe you just
jumped on, but yes, Spirit of Prophecy
is is available here. Um,
all right. So, uh, I'm gonna go ahead
and scroll down. Now, I want you to see
this. I can ask G's.
[clears throat and cough]
By the way, you see these things right
here? These are called sparks.
So, a spark
is basically
as you're typing what you're typing out,
the software is thinking, "Oh, that's a
good thought, and here's a connection
for that thought." So, every time you
see one of these sparks, it's basically
the software
responding in real time
to what you're writing. All right, just
so that you know when you see these pop
up, it's it's continually teaching you,
hey, what about this connection? What
about this connection? Again, again,
it's not thinking for you, but it's it's
trying to get you to expand
the way you think about the Bible. All
right? So, I put in my thought and I can
say, "Hey, add a layer. I want you to
add sanctuary typology. I want you to
add parallels or patterns or the great
controversy theme or feast connections."
I can choose any one of these, but I'm
just going to go ahead and go down. I
can click analyze my thought or I can
turn on scholar mode.
And then I'm going to click analyze.
And what's going to happen
is that it will analyze this thought.
And analyzing the thought is going to
tell me, well, let me just let it pop
up.
How you guys doing so far?
Um,
all right. I'm kind of Give me one
second here. Okay, here we go.
Okay.
So,
here is the analysis of my thought,
right? Um,
okay. So
analysis
an analysis of Christ statement born
again is central to the new covenant
spiritual uh spiritual transformation
the term and it begins to go on and it's
just giving me a whole breakdown of my
thought an entire breakdown of my
thought here's 0.1 here's point 2 and
obviously because of time I'm not going
to read through here's three,
right? It's giving me verse connections.
Um, then it's going to bring all of the
thought together. The student has made a
highly and a highly insightful and
theologically robust connection. The
journey from the literal labor to
spiritual rebirth and from an exclusion
an exclusive priesthood to the
priesthood of all believers demonstrates
a profound understanding of progressive
revelation and typology. The sanctuary
with this ritual washing at the labor
serve as a powerful pedal pedagalog
pedigog
Oh boy, we gonna ped
Oh boy, I'm getting tongue tied. I'm
sorry y'all. Tool to teach Israel about
this necessity of purification for
approaching a holy God and for
priesthood service. What was limited and
ritualistic in the old covenant finds
its expansive and spiritual fulfillment
in the new covenant through Christ.
Being born again of water and of spirit
is precisely the limitation into this
royal priesthood, empowering believers
to draw near to God and offer spiritual
sacrifices. So final verdict is going to
tell me, hey, lean into this, tighten
this, avoid this.
You guys,
when I tell you
that this software is amazing and here's
the here's the score. Doctrinal
integrity 92,
right? Biblical accuracy, theological
depth, all of this. Now, uh here are the
strengths of the thought. Here are areas
of growth and then misinterpretations to
avoid
um palace mapping. So what are the
principles that were used uh in this in
this thought of or can be connected to
this thought? Typo typical layers. Whoa,
my tongue is having a tough time
tonight. And [clears throat]
hold on. Deeper insights you may have
missed. So now it's going to say, have
you thought about this? Have you thought
about that? For example, the name
Nicodemus or the labor's washing wa the
labor's water used for cleansing can be
connected to the ongoing battle against
the seed of the serpent. And it goes on
to explain why, right? All of this you
guys just from the analyze my thought.
Now, it's going to give you verses,
further study, etc. Encouragement from
Jes. Now, you can continue the
conversation. Okay, I like this. So, let
me ask this then. And as you go on, it's
going to continue the conversation. You
can save your analysis. If I scroll all
the way back up to the top here
um with this thought, okay, you're going
to see several more options. So, for
example, um [clears throat] you can
click save to gems. Now, you might
remember on the first floor of the
palace, there was a gems room. And the
gems room is where you kind of store
little aha moments that you get like,
"Oh man, that's a gem. I can use that at
some point in the future for a sermon,
for a Bible study. I don't want to
forget that gem. I'm storing it in the
gems room." You can take this analysis,
right, and store it in the gems room.
You could save it to your studies. You
can export this study. Now, I want to
show you this real quick. Drill this
thought. Drill this thought. So, under
the under the uh analyze my thoughts
tab,
if I click drill this thought, what it's
going to do [cough and clears throat]
is it's going to take this thought and
it's now going to
funnel that thought through all 37 rooms
of the palace.
This is
this is
what is also called the
gather the fragments tab. Gather the
fragments tab. So remember when Jesus
said to the disciples, "Gather the
fragments that remain that nothing be
lost." The whole idea behind gathering
the fragments is the ability to take,
for example, the shortest verse in the
Bible, Jesus wept, and and expound and
drill that text until you are you are
able to connect it
in a far greater capacity
with other truths of the Bible than just
going, "Oh, Jesus wept. That's all there
is to that text. Let me move on."
Drilling the thought is taking a
particular thought and basically
funneling it through all 37 rooms of the
palace. That's what it's doing right
now. It's actually searching through all
37 rooms. Now, let me say this.
Remember that in each room there are
multiple principles.
So, I can I can redrill. What it's going
to do in this first drill is it's going
to choose one principle from every room
and then come together with a package. I
can redrill the entire I can redrill the
same text and now it's going to go
through a total new set of principles
from each room and bring it to another
uh uh bring a whole another conclusion
based upon that thought. You can drill a
text, you can drill a thought. I need
y'all to see how deep this thing goes.
Everybody, once again, I'mma put it in
the chat
so you can see uh where you can you can
experiment with the app. You got seven
days you can just experiment with the
app. It is and I'm going to get ready to
jump off here, guys, because I'm on
longer than I intended. But um
here is here is the site
photoologybible.com.
photo theologybible.com.
Okay, there it is right there.
Um, so you guys the purpose of this of
this this software is it's not just an
esort where you can look up definitions
and you know look up Bible verses. It's
not just a logos where you can do that
and look at different commentaries. But
this software,
this program is helping you to learn how
to think, how to think photo
theologically. It's not designed to to
study for you. It's designed to help you
go beneath the surface.
All right. [clears throat]
So guys, [cough]
this is
this is a short I know I said short just
now, but this is a short overview of the
app. All right. Um
the next time we talk, I will share with
you about the community page. I will
share you with you about the research
option, the sermon builder, which does
not write your sermons for you. It only
helps you. Um,
you can create series
if you're trying to do a Bible study.
You're trying to lead out a Bible study
for a small group or you want to lead
out a Bible study for a classroom or,
you know, for a a Sabbath school series
or whatever it might be. You can
actually create your own series of Bible
studies. Um there's the achievement page
uh which shows you kind of tracks how
you're doing in the app, what you're
doing, what you've accomplished in the
app. Um there is the encyclopedia,
there is your your personal notes there,
all the different libraries. There is
the game page. I haven't even t there is
the game page. You can see the different
people leading in what games that
they've been playing. But there are
different games all based on all based
on a photoology palace that is teaching
you um that is teaching you how to use
the photoology principles
in game form.
Okay.
So,
um
I'm going to go ahead and lock it out
here, guys. Uh, if any of you have any
questions,
um, if you have any issues with the app,
if you're in the app, email me through
the app. If you're not in the app, email
me at a burninghammergmail.com.
You got questions, hey, I'm trying to
get on and I may be having this I'm
having this issue or whatever, email me
at a burninghammergmail.com.
Let me put it in the chat for you. And I
hope you guys put a one in the chat if
you are excited about this app because
listen y'all, I I've been working on
this thing for quite some time. And
boy,
um I'm excited every time I
use this software. I'm excited every
time I use this thing. Um okay, so
here's my email address, guys.
and then we're going to go ahead and
wrap this up. So,
all right. So, for some reason,
I'm unable to put my email in here, but
I'll put it in the link underneath this
video, but again, a burning hammer
atgmail.com.
Now, [clears throat]
uh Nadet, I hope I said that right. This
is there is a lot. It's a palace, right?
It's a palace. So, there's going to be a
lot of rooms and there's going to be a
lot to explore.
So, [snorts]
keep that in mind as you're look. You're
like, "Look at all these tabs. Look at
all these things this thing can do."
Just start small. start with something
that you're like, "Okay, uh let me start
with the devotions or let me start with
just using the the the photo theology
study Bible or let me just start on the
reading plan, right?" Uh uh just start
small and don't be overwhelmed at how
much
this software can do. Okay? Um the more
you use it, the more familiar you are
going to become with it. Go to the
palace. go to the rooms and just stay
locked in on a room. Just say, "All
right, teach me uh help me to understand
this connect six room or you know the
the mathematics room or the dimensions
room." And yes, the spirit will help you
navigate. All right, guys. So, um with
that said, by the way, yes, there is a
subscription. Now, let me say this. I
and I thank you for asking.
For those of you that are on that are
already
um subscribers on my Patreon account,
you're in the photo theology class, um
you're subscribing at at uh one of the
levels of
uh of my Patreon page.
This
Bible software will be available to you
without extra charge. If you're already
a Patreon and you're in one of my uh one
of my classes, one of my courses, you're
supporting the ministry um at a certain
level, you you will have access, as long
as you're in Patreon, you will have
access to this without having to
subscribe
um and pay anything extra. This is this
is um this money this this software
costs money monthly to keep up and
going. So that's why there's a
subscription um for those of you that
are not in the Patreon. And by the way,
oh boy, I will put my Patreon page
um underneath the link in this tab. Now,
if you decide to sign up on my Patreon
account, you're not only going to get
the app, you're also going to get access
to other things that we have on Patreon,
right? So, that's classes, courses, etc.
If you're a patron,
you don't need to subscribe to this app.
You will get automatic access to this
app. And if you want to become a patron
to get access to this app, as well as
the other stuff, my my courses, etc.,
ETA, you can go to the Patreon page.
It's um I'm going to put it in the link
uh because I cannot for some reason
can't type in the chat right now and I'm
not sure why. Um if you are not
on my Patreon page,
then there are you have a 7-day free
trial and then there are two
subscriptions. You can either do the $9
subscription, which is the essential, or
you can do the $15 a month subscription
in which you get access to everything.
Um, that's including the audio bible,
the audio bible commentary. Uh, so those
are the three you it's you can test it
out for seven days, the full thing um
for free, seven days. So, those are the
ways you get access
um to the software.
Uh, okay guys, [clears throat]
with that said, I'm going to go ahead
and close out. Um, I hope that you guys
have uh enjoyed what you have heard
tonight. Uh, once in the in the
software, you can communicate, you know,
with uh with other people in the app.
So, it's also um um interactive uh in
multiple ways.
Get on it, guys. Use it and take your
Bible study to a whole new level. All
right. Peace. God bless you. And uh I
will see you all on the next I'm going
to, by the way, I'll make a playlist on
my YouTube channel just for the photo
theology study app. What I'm going to be
doing is I'm going to be going through
each room and just using the app to show
you the principles of each room. So, I'm
gonna kind of be taking you through the
photo theology principles while showing
how the app works with it. All right.
So, guys, with that said, God bless you
and uh have a good evening, have a good
week. Uh until next time, you all be
blessed.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Be
blessed. Remember, I'll put the Patreon
link uh up in the video in the
description of the video after the video
is over. All right.